Class of 1896 Records, 1892-1961
Smith College Archives
Class of 1896 Records
1892-1961
Smith College. Class of 1896.
RG 80 UUID:bafeab4e-9516-4eb8-bfa0-f14a62a0f178
15 boxes (10.4 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1896, as well as individual student files.
Historical Note
The Class of 1896 was the eighteenth entering class and the eighteenth graduating class of Smith College.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Class of 1896 records, 1892-1961, contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1896, including materials from commencement, reunions, senior dramatics, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia.
Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, and class notes.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1896 records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Baccalaureate Service 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 1)
- Class History 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 2)
- Class Secretary Correspondence 1960-1961 (Box 1514, Folder 3)
- Commencement 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 4)
- Commencement Photos 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 5)
- Commencement Music 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 6)
- Commencement Speaker 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 7)
- Freshman Frolic 1892 (Box 1514, Folder 8)
- Groups 1892-1896 (Box 1514, Folder 9)
- Ivy Day 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 10)
- Ivy Day Photos 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 11)
- Junior Reception given by Class of 1897 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 12)
- Junior Prom 1895 (Box 1514, Folder 13)
- Junior Ushers 1895 (Box 1514, Folder 14)
- Letters 1896-1940 (Box 1514, Folder 15)
- Organizations 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 16)
- Publications 1916 (Box 1514, Folder 17)
- Senior Reception 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 18)
- Sophomore Reception 1892 (Box 1514, Folder 19)
- Songs n.d. (Box 1514, Folder 20)
- Class Supper 1896 (Box 1514, Folder 21)
- Reunions: photographs 1906-1941 (Box 1515, Folder 1)
- Reunions 1896-1916 (Box 1515, Folder 2)
- Reunions: Decennial 1906 (Box 1515, Folder 3)
- Reunions 1911 (Box 1515, Folder 4)
- Reunions: Sophia Smith Homestead 1916 (Box 1515, Folder 5)
- Reunions 1916 (Box 1515, Folder 6)
- Reunions 1921 (Box 1515, Folder 7)
- Reunions 1931 (Box 1515, Folder 8)
- Reunions 1936 (Box 1515, Folder 9)
- Reunions 1941 (Box 1515, Folder 10)
- Reunions 1946 (Box 1515, Folder 11)
- Reunions 1951 (Box 1515, Folder 12)
- Reunions 1956 (Box 1515, Folder 13)
- Reunions: Songs n.d. (Box 1515, Folder 14)
- Reunions: Memorabilia n.d. (Box 1515, Folder 15)
- Senior Dramatics 1896 (Box 1516, Folder 1)
- Senior Dramatics: Photographs 1896 (Box 1516, Folder 2)
- Senior Dramatics: Photographs 1896 (Box 1516, Folder 3)
- Senior Dramatics: Photographs 1896 (Box 1516, Folder 4)
- Senior Dramatics: Photographs 1896 (Box 1516, Folder 5)
- Senior Dramatics: Photographs 1896 (Box 1516, Folder 6)
- Costumes (Box OV)